<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory on Ron Reaser</title>
    <link>/tags/theory/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theory on Ron Reaser</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Ron Reaser</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/tags/theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>CS 310</title>
      <link>/project/cs310/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cs310/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mastery of college algebra. Intermediate Java programming in &lt;a href=&#34;../cs111&#34;&gt;CS 111&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-book fa-2x fa-pull-left fa-border&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Upon successful completion of this course, students will understand the imperative paradigm (viz. procedural languages), declarative paradigm (viz. functional and logical languages), structured paradigm (viz. block and object-orientation), context-free grammars, Backus-Naur form, syntax derivations, operational semantics, denotational semantics, axiomatic semantics, finite-state automata, regular expressions, recursive descent parsers, language translation, declarations, expressions, assignments, data types, control structures, procedures, and abstract data types. Students will be able to identify these concepts in different languages and apply them to practical tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;textbook&#34;&gt;Textbook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;required&lt;/strong&gt; text is &lt;em&gt;Concepts of Programming Languages&lt;/em&gt; 10th Edition &lt;code&gt;ISBN 978-0-13-139531-2&lt;/code&gt; by Robert Sebesta for reading, reference, and assignment. Note that this is not the latest edition. Because most of the out-of-class work will be completed in groups, it is permissible for multiple students, typically within a group, to share a limited number of copies by mutual agreement rather than each student owning their own individual copy, as long as each group member has reasonable and timely access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS 440</title>
      <link>/project/cs440/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cs440/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software engineering in CS 230.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details for this course are pending. &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-circle-o-notch fa-spin fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;textbook&#34;&gt;Textbook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no assigned textbook.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
